TWENTY-FOUR DAYS before Christmas
This , is what 's been worrying me .
Turning sample number 76 from 1300 foot .
We finally found something else than just plain rocks and dirt .
Have a look for yourself , sir .
Sawdust .. Hmm .
At first I thought we drilled into some old tree or something .
But , no .
This level of sawdust is 65 foot thick .
It doesn 't add up , it doesn 't make sense .
It does .
In the olden days people used to store ice by encasing it in sawdust .
Yea , but what do you mean , what are you trying to say .
This mountain , it 's like a giant icebox .
For storing , what ?
- Drill deeper and you will see .
Well , I am .. They 're drilling as we speak
- Make sure everyone has one of these . - What are these ?
It 's the new safety instructions .
Wash behind the ears .
This is funny shit !
Watch your mouth !
It 's Christmas time .
So , let 's act like it .
KORVATUNTURI mountain drill site
Hey , someone 's coming .
Mr. Green , I think we found something .
Sample number 98 .
I think you were right .
Always believe , always .
Gentlemen , listen up .
My dream , since my early childhood
Is about .. to come true .
I can proudly say ,
That we are standing on the sacred grave ..
Biggest burial mound in the world .
Something 's been buried here .
This remarkable place puts even the pyramids to shame .
It took the Saami-People of Lapland centuries to build this mound ,
You have 24 days to open it .
Roll up the sleeves , prepare the dynamite , do what you do best !
They 're going to blow up this mountain .
We have a grave to rob .
Juuso !
Juuso ! Wait !
Santa 's been buried .
Juuso ! Is Santa Claus dead ?
Idiot , you still believe in Santa Claus ?
You 're such a little kid . Come on already .
- So they 've lied to us this whole time . - At least to you .
What Santa came to our home then ?
Piiparinen , haven 't you realized that ?
Piiparinen ? Do you think Dad knows ?
Your dad pays him for it .
Don 't you understand , kid ?
The whole Santa business is a fraud .
The Truth About Santa Claus .
First Santa Claus .
Have you been naughty ?
Santa walks barefoot in the snow .
Santa making Christmas-Stew .
1 day before Christmas
Pietari !
Wake up ! Wake up , son !
Pietari ! Are you awake ?
- Yea , yea . - Then get up , and get cleaned up !
Bad Vuppe . You were supposed to keep watch .
Dad !
Come here , Dad !
Come inside if you have something to say .
I don 't want to .
Then go back in the house . I don 't want you outside alone .
For real ! I 've got something important to tell you .
For real . Wolves are going to eat you ,
And I 'm not kidding , you hear ?
Dad , I 'm coming .
Close your eyes , little man . Your dad 's working .
- You shouldn 't have turned off the lights . - Who 's going to be looking at them at night ?
- Were you on the roof ? - Wha ?
Under my window ?
Pietari , I 'm too busy to answer stupid questions .
- Were you , or not ? - No , I was not there .
Perhaps the chimney sweep ?
Go get dressed , chop chop .
- We 've got to go . - Where ?
Don 't you remember what day it is ?
Oh , right , it 's reindeer round up day . Am I going too ?
I 'd think you were already dressed .
He 's spying on us .
This is yours now .
Is it loaded ?
Of course , it 's not much use unloaded .
And take off those glasses .
Got a light ?
Where is your father ?
They had to take the snowmobiles ,
Piiparinen couldn 't get the chopper started .
Everybody off the fence !
Three , two , one !
Can you even use that thing , squirt ?
Of course .
- Are you going to shoot Santa Claus ? - He was outside my window yesterday
I thought you said he 's dead . Try to make up your mind .
- Doing some electrical work ? - You like my handiwork ?
Got to try something , there 's predators about .
The explosions are driving them crazy .
I wonder what they are looking for .
Some kind of research .
Hey , Check it out .
They 're coming .
Dad ! Dad !
They 're coming !
Our refrigerators will soon be filled with meat .
Open the gate . Get out from under foot .
Come ! Come in , what are you doing there .
- Two skinny little runts - Something 's wrong
Maybe the others have just lost their way ?
No , they haven 't .
Merry Christmas to you .
- You stay here . - Me too ?
Look after Pietari .
What kind of a wolf makes a mess like this ?
A big and fucking nasty one . Look at this .
All because of those idiots and their explosions .
Now we 've got Russian wolves here too .
They found the hole .
Rauno , it 's been cut with forceps .
It 's our fault .
Not a word to your father , or I 'll kick your ass !
We never went anywhere near that fence , remember that .
- They deserve to be shot . - They 're probably gone already .
They are already gone . The last few days were very quiet .
Fuck , if it wasn 't for the border , I 'd kick all their asses .
You 've got insurance , right ?
No , we don 't fucking have insurance .
Four hundred and thirty three carcasses .
Aimo , how much will it cost ?
About 85 thousand .
Plus VAT , twenty two percent .
There 's our money , rotting away .
He was very hungry .
So , what do we do now ?
Let 's go talk to them .
Fuck .
I hear they 've paid off the border patrol ,
To shoot trespassers on sight .
Crossing the border is a big deal .
Bankruptcy is also no small thing .
Pietari , come on !
This is a shitty idea !
They left in a hurry . Fuck !
Come see this !
Enlarged area
They found him Vuppe .
Seismic research , bullshit . They 've been digging for something .
What the hell did they find ?
That 's the end of that .
What are you doing ? Aren 't you going to open it ?
No .
- Tape these to your butt - Are you serious ?
Do I look like I am ?
You look , like you 're wearing diapers .
So this is why you called me here ?
Look at these .
The real Santa was a bit different , the Coca Cola Santa is a fraud .
These are from a story book .
This one isn 't .
- What is this ? - Evidence that some stories are real .
And what should I be seeing here ?
The real Santa ..
.. Who whips naughty children to death . Their blood spraying all over ..
.. Until there 's nothing left of them , not even the bones .
But how did he end up there ?
A long time ago , the Saami-People were angry at him ,
They lured him onto a frozen lake .
When Santa came , the ice broke under him .
Santa fell in and the lake froze completely trapping him .
When summer came , they pulled up a huge ice block ,
They then buried it under several hundred meters of dirt and stones .
- And that became known as Korvatunturi . - Yep .
You 're such a tool !
- When was the last time you got spanked ? - Dunno . When I was little .
Should we tell them ?
Listen , kiddo , do you have any idea what your dad 's going to do ..
When he hears those reindeer died .. because of you ?
- Are you making gingerbread ? - Are you hungry ?
Yes .
- Did you play hockey ? - No , just playing make-believe .
Must be a rough game .
Yes .
These are really good , just like mother used to make them .
Glad to hear that .
Dad ?
What if I didn 't exist ?
What do you mean ?
If I had disappeared .
You should disappear ... into your bed . It 's already very late .
Dad , do you think I 've been nice ?
Nice boys are already in bed at this hour .
Merry Christmas , Dad .
Merry Christmas , Pietari .
- This is Subzero one . - Finally !
I 've tried contacting you a thousand times ! Where are you ?
- Is the cargo ready ? - No !
We have to cancel the whole operation !
It 's not what you think !
- I repeat . Is the cargo ready ? - Cargo ?
Don 't you understand ?
It still has a pulse !
Calm down , Mr. Green ,
Just follow the safety instructions .
Fuck your safety instructions !
What the fuck ?
CHRISTMAS
Stay there , I 'll check it out .
Do you think this is funny ? ! You nearly killed me !
You 're definitely not going skating !
You 're grounded for Christmas .
I 'm going for a pee .
Come on , Vuppe , let 's go out .
Dad ! .. DAD !
- What 's wrong ? - The bait 's been taken
Carefully now .
Stay there .
Did you hear me ?
Don 't come any closer .
Some bird ..
What is it ?
There 's nothing there .
- Can I take a look then ? - No .
Some kind of a bird snatched the bait .
- I want to see it ! - See what ? There 's nothing there .
Then why can 't I look ?
Because we haven 't even had breakfast yet .
Hey .. We really don 't have anything else ?
These are fine .
If I eat all of these .. Then can I go take a look ?
Then you take some more .
Are you angry at me ?
No .
You wait here .
Did you hear me ? !
You 're still grounded .
- What the fuck took you so long ? - Had to get ready for the Santa gig
Follow me and keep your mouth shut .
Vuppe , come on .
Serves him right for trespassing , god damned .
Greene , Brian , Jonathan .
Born in - 52 .
One of those nuts from the mountain .
Under 60 years old .
What are you going to say ?
To whom ?
People .
Nothing .
You probably are aware that wolf pits are illegal ..
God damn you , Piiparinen !
Whether you like it or not , you 're involved in this .
- I ought to .. - Be silent ,
And think .. If you know how .
I have exactly one hour , before my first Santa gig .
Vuppe , stay .
Did you see ?
He 's breathing . Tough old guy .
What 's he doing ?
He 's scenting something .
Pietari .
Pietari !
I told you to stay inside !
Pietari ! Get back here right now !
- Did he see ? - Well , what do you think ?
Hey , I 've gotta get to work .
What do I do with that one ?
Chitchat with him .
Shit !
Pietari , Pietari . God damned . ... God damned .
What is he up to ?
- Afternoon . - Hello
- What he hell sort of a dress are you wearing ? - What ?
- Is everything all right ? - What do you mean ?
Horrible ghostly figure ...
.. Been going around town .
Strange things have happened .
Everything 's fine with us , isn 't that right Pietari ?
Then you 're an exception .
I see the whole murder squad showed up .
- What 's messed up here then ? - My side-business .
Couple of hundred sacks of potatoes , the whole harvest .
I 'm here for potatoes ?
Yes ! .. And no .
They just took the bags .
Holy hell ..
Last night nearly every house got their heaters stolen .
Ripped right out of the walls .
It 's going to be a damn cold Christmas .
Inkeri 's hair blower was stolen from the bathroom .
Who would need all that old crap ?
Listen . Our junk is high tech to the Russians .
- Pietari , shouldn 't we be heading home now ? - No .
- Where 's Juuso ? - Probably still asleep
Pietari !
Not so fast .
Let 's take a look at your car .
Juuso .
Juuso , wake up . He 's at our place now .
Juuso ?
Juuso has been taken !
- What 's this ? - It was in Juuso 's bed .
Maybe he 's snuck out to see a girl .
When I was your age , we used to make a building out of pillows and ..
- Pretended it 's ... - He 'll probably be home by nightfall .
- You still don 't understand ? - Pietari ! Nobody wants to listen to your nonsense .
- Now I can go ? - Yes , go .
Aimo , you speak English , right ?
Why ?
We need a translator .
Oh shit .
Hello Old devil .
Gingerbread ?
So , who am I translating for ? I have other things to do .
We have guests from Korvantunturi .
- What kind of guests ? - American guests .
Get inside now .
- But dad , we have to help Juuso ! - Nonsense , Juuso is a big boy .
Well ?
You can not go there , he 's not human .
- Not a human ? - Not human !
- He bit me , damned ! - Well , well ..
- This I have to see . - No , really , don 't ..
Look at that . There 's something about him , something odd .
- Am I right ? - He 's foreign ..
Go talk to him .
Be careful .
How do you like the land of the Northern Lights ?
I 'm not going there alone .
Understood .
Cover me .
This does nothing .
Wake up , Grandpa !
We need money .
Pietari here , hi . Sorry to bother you on Christmas Eve , but is Hemppa home ?
Oh , he isn 't ... Well , thanks anyway .
No , haven 't seen . Oh , and Merry Christmas to you . Bye .
Give me the broom .
Where are your friends ?
Ask him what they dug out of the mountain .
What did you dig inside the mountain ?
Pretending to be deaf ; old trick .
Tell him , we 're keeping him here until someone pays .
- Like , as a hostage ? - Yes !
Explain !
We keep you here ' til somebody pay .
- You 're going to make him mad ! - He doesn 't understand .
This is just the first phase .
Last chance , asshole ,
Rauno here will ask the next question ; he don 't speak English .
- What the fuck was that ? - Dad !
Oh no , what does he want now ?
Dad , we need to talk .
Pietari ... Piiparinen and I are in the middle of something . What is it ?
Spank me .
- Wha ? - I need to get spanked .
Fifteen good strokes ought to do it .
What is wrong with you ?
I 've been naughty .
What have you done ?
We went to Korvatunturi even after you told me not to .
Juuso and I made the hole in the fence .
You did what ?
I 'm the last one . Everyone else has been taken , Juuso too .
What is this nonsense ?
They took all of the children .
Rauno , you gotta see this .
Wait for me here .
He 's up to something .
See ? He bit through this .
Look at his eyes .
What is he seeing ?
Pietari !
No !
Do you know this guy ?
Looks like he knows you .
He knows all the children in the world .
Who is he ? Answer me !
He 's been spying on us the whole time .
What do you mean ? Speak up !
He 's Santa Claus .
He came to get me . They dug him out at Korvatunturi .
A god damn fantastical creature ! I knew there was something odd about him !
- He 's coming right for us ! - Dad , don 't let him take me !
Get on the ground ! Tell him .. Translate it for him ! .. Get down on the ground !
Down ! Down boy ! Go down !
He has his own language .
- He is not afraid of you , Dad ! - Yes , he is
Tie him up .
- I 'm not touching it . - Right now !
What was that ?
Subzero One , do you read me ?
It 's coming from the jacket . Be careful .
Mr. Green ? Is everything okay ?
- We are landing in 30 Minutes . - What did she say ?
They want him back .
Mr. Green ?
Is Santa ready to fly ?
- I 'm right , aren 't I ? - What are you going to do ?
This is Rauno . Rauno from Finland .
We have Santa Claus .
Who is this ? Where is Mr. Green ?
Tell them ... that we have Santa for sale .
How much are you going to ask for it ?
- Enough to cover my debts . - At least .
- We should think about this . - Are you afraid ?
We 're giving it up way too easy .
Think about how much it might cost .
A real Santa Claus .
Someone is going to get rich from it .
That 's what we 're doing .
- Dad ! - Stay here , this won 't take long .
- It 's Inkeri 's hair dryer ! - What the fuck ?
Put the fucking thing away ,
And try to look like you mean business .
Fucking little midget .
Who are you ?
Where are my men ?
- Say something . - Yea , yea ; we are men .
Let 's do business .
Business ? What kind of business ?
What do you want ?
- How much do we want ? - 85 thousand .
85 thousand dollars .
- At minimum a million . - You shut up .
Hey ... Where is the cargo ?
The last door ..
Shh , put down your weapons and smile ..
As nice as you can .
Move slowly and do exactly as I say .
- What did he say ? - We need to stay quiet .
This is not Santa .
What ?
It 's one of Santa 's little helpers .
- What ... fucking helper ? - He says it 's an elf .
Enough of that bullshit , ... show me the money !
God damned . Santa is going to find out who is naughty or nice .
What happened to him ?
Is someone there ?
What the fuck is that thing running there ?
What the hell is happening here ?
They 're protecting their master .
Pietari ! Pietari !
Pietari !
The Elves have built a nest for it .
.. For what ?
- Is that .. ? - Yes .
They 're trying to defrost it .
- Dad . - Shh , that was that ?
Help , Daddy !
Juuso . They are all here . And about to get spanked .
Juuso , where are you ?
- Kill the heaters ! - Juuso , say something !
- Piiparinen , the door won 't hold ! - What should I do ?
Pile stuff at the door !
We need to barricade it ! Hurry !
Aimo , leave the brat there and come help us !
My son .
- Daddy , I want to go home ! - We 're all right , we 're going home soon .
We 're all going to die !
Dad !
Aimo !
Piiparinen !
Listen to me !
As long as Santa is here ,
The elves will not leave kids alone .
It 's either me , or Santa ;
I suggest Santa .
This is Piiparinen . Pietari , you read me ?
Pietari , read you fine .
- Ready for takeoff . - Roger .
- Why do I have to be in the sack ? - Because it 's my plan ! Let 's go .
- Here 's another one . - Not Juuso .
All of the children must be together , otherwise this won 't work .
I 'm scared , Dad .
Piiparinen ! The package is ready !
- Aren 't you going to get cold out there ? - You stay out of this !
Dad , don 't worry , everything will be fine !
Cleared for takeoff !
You take care of your part , I 'll take care of this !
Slow down ! We 'll wait for them here !
Piiparinen , look down !
I can 't believe it , they 're following us .
What did I say .
Piiparinen , let 's turn back .
- What ? - Let 's fly to the corral !
What do you mean ?
Pretend they 're reindeer !
Reindeer ?
Fuck yea ! That 's what we 're going to do !
I guess we were a bit Naughty .
If you ever wondered , Aimo , how Santa manages to visit thousands ..
Of places simultaneously , ... this is how .
Magic of Christmas .
Piiparinen , the gate is closed !
God damned . We have to think of something else .
There 's no time , I 'll open the gate !
You 're not going anywhere !
I can not land there to pick you back up .
I 'm not coming back .
Pietari ? Do you hear me ?
Pietari !
Piiparinen !
Tell Daddy what I did !
Dad ..
A peaceful Christmas to all ..
And a fucking banging New Year .
Feast your eyes on that , bastards !
What happened ?
A Christmas miracle . Congratulations , Pietari !
You just made all the elves unemployed .
Take the kids home , it 's way past their bedtime .
Roger , and out .
One hundred and ninety eight Santa Clauses .
Do the math Juuso , how much will it cost ?
How much for one ?
Eighty-Five thousand .
About 16.800.000 , something like that .
Plus VAT , twenty two percent .
- You 're quite a guy . - You too .
312 days until Christmas
Seventy-Six days before Christmas
There 's nothing for you there , caveman !
TWENTY-FOUR DAYS before Christmas